[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening, good day everybody.
I hope you're all doing very well and
welcome to the 252nd episode of the Ask
a Bijit Show. Let us see who all is
there on the live stream. I can see Bat
first. I can see rashi rat uh vidmanar
anime sankit
zamati geopolitical dub from indor
maverick
veneula yash shadav vinay esman raj
namanadas
shriham I tarun singh chawan mr jam in
for king anan chandak baba abhijit
chava abhishek udai kumar ais manticor
wamshi khalim shrias mitra samar
Daksh abai Jadav
Bargav E Rahul Dunak AVM philosophic
shadow who is a new member welcome my
friend welcome and thank you for joining
me the membership Daksha Pete Vishnu
moharan Airal Gandhi Mr. Jam
Maklavin Namit Dad Nita Das again
Pushana Yashant Sudir Kiadi the Chad Ba
Bali today Dha Beast Place
247 Ara Prabhar Xenomorphosis Push Moria
Karan Vik Rahashia Gata Gata Arnav Singh
Molana Abijit what on earth is that uh
Nan Roshan Janaviar
Adita G, Anish Shintre, Kapalin, Nimish,
Gupta, Tanmo, Chakraarti, Unknown, VS,
Na, Vikas, PJ, Manisha, Cardardo, Anu,
Duptasin, Sam, Drowning, Shrias, Niha,
Sharma, Moria,
Palin, VS, Sena, Nimish, Nikhil,
Vishnav, Vine, Esman, Vikas, Event
Countdown and so many other people. So,
greetings to you all and let's get going
with the questions. I'm sure you have
questions. Uh this will be a 1h hour
live stream roughly in that I'll take as
many questions as I can. So, let's get
going with the questions. I'll first do
the super chats because those are paid
and then if there are no more super
chats we'll we'll take the other
questions as well. Jay Bawani says
Chanaki like coup what resistance we'll
face today. In today's day and age,
Chanak doesn't have to do a coup. He can
simply use the electoral system to come
to power. So there's no need for a coup.
Chanek is not stupid. Chanek was the one
of the most brilliant men who ever ever
existed. So he will not do a coup. He
will simply use the electoral system to
come to power. A mandicor says is the
low Hindu birth rate a symptom of
inflation. I'm not sure it's a symptom
of inflation. It's a symptom of the fact
that um that u
there what's it what is it a symptom of
generally that you're overworked and you
don't have time for your family. That's
typically what a low birth rate is is a
symptom of uh there's too much work that
you need to do in order to earn a living
and as a consequence of that there's not
enough time for family and married life
and that's why there's typically a low
birth rate and obviously not just
inflation but but rising prices and
overall everything is expensive. it. So
you could say it's inflation because if
you look at the situation 30 years ago,
40 years ago, things were not that
expensive. So inflation is a factor and
there are other factors as well.
Right? Bhar says, would it be better for
India to have the presidential form of
governance? I say this from the point of
view that a particular MP seat may not
remain reduced to a mere
number. I am in favor of a presidential
form of government for sure. It's a much
better form of government which is more
suited to a gigantic nation like India,
a subcontinent size nation like India.
The system that we have adopted is the
British system, the the Westminster uh
parliamentary democracy system which is
suitable for a nation like the UA, like
the UK, a small island nation in the
Atlantic Ocean. It's not suitable for a
vast nation like India with a huge
population. the larger your population
and the larger the size of your nation,
the more centralized the system has to
be in order to be effective. So you need
a so so that's why you need a
presidential form of of governance would
be way more beneficial and effective for
a nation like India and right now you're
rightly saying that MP MP seats are just
reduced to numbers. You have I don't
know how many MPs in in the country and
at the end of the day what do they end
up doing over over a period of five
years for their constituency?
uh they actually act act on behalf of
their party and they do whatever the
party says. There's something called
party discipline, right? So whatever the
party says you do it at the end of the
day your constituency may suffer as a
consequence of that. Uh so if you have a
presidential system then the president
doesn't have to worry about you know the
coalition politics and and staying in
staying in power in parliament and not
losing the confidence of your MPs and
the voter and so on and so forth. all
those issues that are such a pain to
handle on a day-to-day basis. If you are
the leader of the country, you have to
focus on governance and leading the
country not on these matters but that's
how what we have today. So I think a
presidential system form of governance
is way better for
India. AVM says why are Hindus refusing
to have kids? I see most of them have at
most one kid and instead treat pets as
the progeni western copycats or medical
issues. There's no medical issues. Um
yeah many many of them are are
influenced by the west many of them
focus on career many of them focus um
see the thing is that if you want to
have high standards high standards of
living a high income etc you have to
work really hard and you work when you
work really hard it means you work
overtime and on so on so forth and then
there's not much time for your family
and today you know it's very expensive
everything's very expensive expensive
medical treatment for kids is expensive.
Education for for kids, if it's
especially if it's good education, it's
super expensive. Lacks of rupees per
year and so on. If you don't care about
your kids, doesn't matter. You can just
dump your kids anywhere on the streets
and they'll grow up on their own. So, if
you want to have good a good upbringing
for your kids, then in this day and age,
it makes sense to have less kids. So,
it's not a medical issue. It's all these
things. When you actually care about
your kids, then you you cannot have so
many kids because then you won't be able
to give them all the same, you know, a
good upbringing, a comfortable
upbringing, right? You will have to
compromise. So, it's better that that
you have less kids. That's the kind of
rationale that seems to be going on. I'm
not saying that's that should it should
be the case. But there are lots of
constraints on people, financial
constraints and job constraints. I mean
there are so few jobs high paying jobs
that if you get one you have to stay you
have to retain that which means you have
to work really hard doubly hard in so
many sectors in India you know it's it's
they expect you to work 12 hours a day
overtime is just just a take you know
it's expected if you work just 8 hours
and you're slacking so there's no work
life balance and so on so you go home
exhausted you just throw you know hit
the bed and then wake up and start the
cycle all over again. So when you have
that that sort of lifestyle or that sort
of situation circumstances, it's very
hard for you have for you to have
multiple kids and especially if you're
living in a metropolitan city where both
the husband and wife are working, how on
earth will they be able to have kids? If
they have kids, who's going to take care
of them, right? If if you bring family
over, then it's going to be an
additional expense for you and maybe
your family can't do that either. So all
these issues are there. But if you don't
care about your kids, if you just want
to produce numbers, then you can have as
many as you want and they will all grow
up illiterate. it doesn't matter. So you
know different perspectives I would
say. Rohan Suna says should the AMCA be
brought under the PMO? What are my
views? My question is how much can the
PMO
handle everything should be brought
under the under the PMO? I I agree that
you know specific high value projects
should certainly come under the PMO. Uh
I think the AMC is doing reasonably
well. I think the jet engine uh issue
should be brought under the PMO. you
know, so very critical issues should
come under the PMO. I think the AMC is
doing overall well. There are no there's
no delay as such. It's on track. If it
goes off track for whatever reason,
potentially in the future, we don't want
it to happen, but if it does, then maybe
it can come under the PMO's
perview. Sahil says, "What's the status
of India's relationship with North
Korea?" We have diplomatic relations
with North Korea. We have visits from
their uh diplomats from time to time. We
have our diplomats going there from time
to time. So it's a decent relationship.
It's
neither significantly friendly, neither
significantly unfriendly. We have
relations and we are aware of of North
Korea's status as a Chinese vasal. We
are aware of uh their activities. In the
past, we've had North Korean cyber
groups who have hacked who have tried
hacking into Indian assets and so on.
So, we have those issues and obviously
that'll happen at China's behest. So,
when when it looks like a North Korean
hack has happened, it essentially means
it's come from China. That sort of
thing. So, I think we have reasonable
relations with North Korea, but nothing
special. Arian, so thank you so much.
Uh, has the Indian government really
thrown 40 illegal reas in international
waters and a few on an island? Till
well, till when can we get rid of
illegal potential terrorists? And what
are your views on one of Trump's
ministers that India has crossed some
red line of the US? Okay. Has the Indian
government really thrown 40 Rohingyas in
international waters? I don't I have not
heard any such report and u I'm not sure
where this report has come from. Uh
maybe they
were maybe they were disembarked from a
boat near a beach maybe you know 10 ft
from a beach or something. So if you do
that then people can claim that you know
you threw them into international waters
or whatever into into the the Bay of
Bengal or something. I'm not sure what
exactly happened but I don't think India
will do any such thing that will you
know be a human rights violation. I
India will not do that. So uh wherever
these reports may or may not have come
from I think we have to scrutinize the
source and what's the actual story and
few on an island. Well, if we have uh
sent some illegal infiltrators to an
island, well, that's okay, right? So,
I'm not sure if it's happened. I'm I'm
what I'm hearing is that we are
deporting Bangladeshi illegal
infiltrators back to Bangladesh through
the border with Bangladesh. That's what
I'm hearing. That's those are confirmed
reports. But these reports of illegal
Rohhingyas in international waters and
and putting them on islands uh I am not
sure that these are
uh that this is true news. Maybe it's
fake news. I'm not sure. Not not 100%
convinced about this. Um till when can
we get rid of illegal potential
terrorists? Look, we have I I imagine I
I it's it's a it's an educated guess.
Say in 2014 the government had
officially said we have 50 million
Bangladeshes in India illegal
infiltrators. It's been more than 11
years since then. So my assessment is
that maybe the number has doubled
because the borders we know how the
situation is. So maybe we have 100
million in India. 100 million it takes
time to evict 100 million people.
Imagine let's say we want to evict 100
million illegals in 10 years. Okay. 10
years which means that we have to evict
we have to deport 10 million per
year. 10 million per year. So 365 days.
So in 36 days you have to deport 1
million. Okay. 1 million in let's say 30
days. So in 3 days you have to evict one
lakh. So every day you have to evict
33,000. That's a huge number. Very hard
to achieve. So maybe it'll take 10 20
years to do this. You see how big the
problem is, how massive the problem is,
how the magnitude of the problem. You
see how big it is. It's going to take a
lot of doing to deport all the illegals.
And it's not just the 100 million
Bangladeshes, you have Rohingyas, you
have cookies, you have Pakistanis, you
have god knows what
else. India has become what what like
they say dham shala. So yeah, it will
take time. Uh my views on Trump's state,
minister statement, India crossed some
red line. I'm not aware of this. I
haven't heard of it. Sorry. Saita uh
from 1600 to 1857 many East India
Company British looters like Elu Yale of
Yale University went to the US. How many
from USA side EIC lutters businesses?
Now it's very hard to assertain you know
unless you do a very detailed impact
analysis. There is a term in in
in the field of uh information
technology IT software development. It's
called impact analysis. It's s it's like
something you do in software maintenance
actually. So we're going to have to do
impact analysis of all the individuals
who served in India as part of the
looting team and how many went to the US
and how many ended up founding
businesses or universities or whatever.
I'm not sure the one that I know of is
Elihu Yale that I spoke about a few
years ago. Then the news news seems to
have spread. Uh but there could be lots
there could be lots. It's possible, but
I haven't gone and done the impact
analysis research, so can't say about
how many more there could be. I'm sure
there are lots
more. Feminist Slayer says, "What's the
mystery of Bermuda Triangle, Alien
Supernatural?" Well, allegedly this
region called the Bermuda Triangle.
Let's let's uh put that on the screen
because we should have a map out here.
Just give me a second. I'll have to u uh
crack open my map. Give me a second and
I'll show you where this place is.
So the Burmuda triangle, where is it?
It's in the region of Burmuda in the
Atlantic Ocean. So let's go. Okay, let's
go westwards from India. Where is
Bermuda? So let's just search for it.
Bermuda Triangle. It's a small patch of
land, a patch of ocean, okay, in the
Caribbean region more or
less east of the Caribbean region which
is called the Bermuda Triangle. And
what's the mystery? It is claimed that
some super supernatural events happen
over there and there are
interdimensional verb holes or god knows
what else you have over there. But the
fact is that if you do a statistical
analysis of how many ships and planes
have disappeared there, it's nothing
statistically different from any other
major you know near land part of the
world. So it is said that there is some
kind of supernatural activity or or what
they what they call paranormal activity
that happens there but I have seen no
evidence of that potential stuff. Um
Sergeant Skylin says why is there no
Rafad source code deal? And we have I
don't know u see look everything is a
price everything in the world is a price
uh at least the French are not you know
as far as I know there's no hidden back
doors or kill switches in the Rafal the
source code if you want it maybe it'll
cost a few billion more I don't know how
it what the what the deal is but
everything in the world has a price and
this is not you know a family
relationship this is a trade
relationship so uh if you want a deal
maybe we'll have to pay more for That's
just how it goes in the world.
Geopolitical dub says will Russia allow
India to sell the bramos to the Middle
East? Well, it depends case by case
basis we have to see. Let's say we want
to sell the bramos to Saudi Arabia
hypothetically completely fictional
situation. Let's say we want to sell it
to Saudi Arabia. Saudi Arabia is a major
US partner. Will Russia allow us to do
it? They will say no. Sorry. Okay. Let's
say we want to sell it to to to for
example Yemen. Well, that will be a big
red line for the US. So, we'll not do
that either. So, it depends. Overall, in
the Middle East, most of the nations are
US allies. And if you sell a weapon
system to U to a US ally, it may end up
in the hands of the US. The US is just
too powerful. They'll arm twist that
ally into giving up one or two systems
for study. So, it's very risky for
Russia to allow the Brahmos to end up in
the hands of a Middle Eastern nation. So
most likely the Russians will say please
don't do that. It's kind of a veto and
we have agreed to a Russian veto on the
bramos. So it's it's an understanding
that we have with
Russia. He's mandicor says do you think
warp engines are a much better
alternative for
FTL? What's
FTL? It's it helps if you see I've got a
very small brain. I don't understand
this is FTL. What's FTL? Faster than
light. Faster than light. Okay. Do you
think warp engines are a much better
alternative for FTL? But all
hypothetical warp engines require some
kind of exotic matter. Is it doable?
This is all science fiction of today.
There's something called the alubar
drive which is kind of a warp drive
which kind of does work within the
constraints of Einstein's field
equations of general relativity. Um I
have not studied it. I haven't studied
studied every single piece of research.
Does it require some kind of exotic
matter? Maybe it does. uh in order to
warp spaceime to that uh to that extent
maybe it does need some kind of exotic
matter or some kind of stupendously
powerful gravitational field perhaps.
How to do it? Is it doable within the
constraints of
presently known technology? Absolutely
impossible. Theoretically according to
the laws of physics it's possible but
for that you will need uh technology
that we simply can't imagine today.
Right?
For example, you you know
wormholes can can exist according to
Einstein's equations.
Okay. But to keep a wormhole open, its
neck open, you need exotic material,
exotic matter, either negative mass
matter or or or a cosmic spring, which
is the topological defect in the fabric
of spaceime
itself. So if these things exist, then
it's doable. But do they exist? We've
never seen it. But they can
theoretically exist. So my point is this
is all science fiction at this point in
time. If we if aliens exist and they are
like they have IQ of 2,000 or something,
they may be able to do it and then their
technology will feel like magic to
us. Rahul Lakshmanan says, "Do you think
modern India has a separation between
government and civil society which did
not exist in ancient bat? Isn't greater
synergy between society and government
better and will we ever get there
again?"
There is a separation between government
and civil society. It did not exist in
ancient par. Absolutely 100% true. We
have adopted the western system. We have
wholeheartedly swallowed the western
system which is not suitable for for a
civilization like India. But we have
accepted it. I mean we have been made to
accept it. Right? In 1947, power was
transfer transferred from by the British
to a bunch of people who did exactly
what the British wanted and India
remained colonized. When decolonization
happens, there will no longer be the
separation between government and civil
society or government and society and
the government will no longer say that
we will not uh we will stay away from
religion and culture, our indigenous
religion and culture. That's not how it
works. So there is the separation and
it's very
unfortunate. In the old days the kings
and emperors were the guardians of
dharma and the constitution of India
which was never there but if there was a
constitution it was the laws of dharma
right that's what it was so it is better
to have our own civilizational system
our age-old traditional civilizational
system it's always worked better for us
will we ever get there again I don't
know I would love to but I can't say I'm
not a fortune teller I can give you
probabilistic scenarios and in if I give
you probabilistic probabilistic
scenarios then there's a small
probability I would say maybe 5% or 10%
in the next 50 years that this happens
maybe a 10% probability in the next 50
years that this happens maybe I can do
probabilistic uh scenario sketching for
this as well so
yeah par maheshwari says economic
geopolitical situation of India in 2013
well the next 5 years are going to be
very difficult
very hard to negotiate so much is going
to change a lot will change. Apparently,
there's an invasion of Taiwan happening
in 20 2027. Before that, we could have
the end of Pakistan potentially. Who
knows? Maybe it won't happen because
China steps in and then maybe we could
face a two front war situation. We have
no idea what's going to happen. Next 5
years are going to be very turbulent,
very chaotic. But let's
give a most likely scenario, an
optimistic scenario.
Um if if we play the game right, then we
will obviously be the third largest
economy in the world. And it's possible
that if we play the game right then in
2030 you may not have Pakistan, you may
have multiple independent nations over
there. If we play the game right and
that would be advantage India if that
happens. Uh so hopefully that's where we
are in 20130 but can't say for sure
obviously. Um Wamshi Khalim says when
should we get monarchy before become
number one in GDP?
M when should we get
monarchy? I would love to have Chandra
Gupta Mory as our emperor today or
Kaneshka as our emperor today or maybe
Rajendra Chula or maybe the great
Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj or maybe
Kumar Gupta or Sand
Gupta. I would love to have it today but
when so if when should we have it? We
should have it today. Those people had
such high standards compared to what we
have today. Um but when could we have
it? Absolutely no way of saying
uh maybe a 10% probability like I said
in the next 50 years and possibly in 50
years we could become number one in GDP
possibly if uh if if the gods and the
stars align with us.
Philosophic Shadow says, "Could you
suggest some relevant career options for
a second year BCOM student considering
today's time?" Bachelor of
Commerce. What do you do as a bachelor
of commerce? What are you learning? I
have no idea about BCOM. I mean, I do
have a broad understanding. Um, I think
if you're in commerce, then you should
go into business or
entrepreneurship. Uh, of course that's
always high risk. Business is always
high risk. Entrepreneurship is always
high risk. If you want a low risk
option, you go and get a job and that's
a steady income. Then you spend a
certain
time. Beyond that, I don't know what to
say because BCOM means for me it's only
business. So you go into the business
sector as far as I
understand. Um but if you want to do
well in life and maybe if you have the
appetite for taking risks then you
should start some kind of business, get
some kind of investment or maybe
if family helps and you can get have
family invest something. Uh so yeah
without knowing you personally I really
don't know what to say what advice to
give you. It's only when I know you
personally or at least speak to you for
five minutes face to face and get some
some kind of orientation and some kind
of perspective that I could give you
some actual advice without that I can
just give very general u advice which
may actually not help you very
much says yes I have discussed this just
a while ago Russia is offering the SU57E
export variant with full source code
access and transfer of technology is
this believable but as far as I know
dual It is dual engine, not single
engine. Oh, thank the gods it's dual
engine. I prefer a dual engine aircraft.
It's more powerful. It's more reliable.
Why would you want a single engine
aircraft? Why? Of course, you have it.
It can play a certain role like the
Tjas. It's a single engine aircraft with
short legs. It's an interceptor. It's
not for long range operations. Uh the
Sukoy
57E is a different kind of beast. It's a
fifth generation fighter plane with the
some stealth characteristics and it's
definitely a high quality fighter
plane. Um so if you get full source code
access, if you get transfer of
technology and if you get to build it in
India and if you get to integrate all
your indigenous defense systems into it
and if it also has interoperability
interoperability with the Sukoy 30 that
we already use which means that we could
use you know already existing
infrastructure for it then what else do
you
want? I think there's a high possibility
that by the end of the year after you
know assessing the offer and making some
amendments to it there's a high
possibility about 80% in my opinion that
by the end of this year we'll go ahead
with this so I look forward to it
happening I'll be very happy if it
happens. Nandanda Kishor says, "How to
consolidate power as a leader? Eliminate
all potential
challengers." That's
it. Malik said says, "Chemical
engineering versus robotics AI. What's
the best for
future? Chemical engineering versus
robotics AI. I think robotics has a
great future. I think robotics
integrated with AI has an even better
future. Chemical engineering could be
all automated.
It will be automated to a very large
extent. You have catalytic converters
and chemical reactors
and whatever the processes that I forget
right now. It's been a long time since I
studed chemistry. But all of that can be
automated. All of it. And automatons
will do a much better job than humans of
of running the processes and supervising
and monitoring everything and uh
ensuring the right kind of uh results. I
think robotics and AI or
robotics merged with AI has the best
potential future. So yeah, if you have
the choice of taking one or the either,
I would go with robotics and AI. If I
was in a position, if I had these two
choices, I would without thinking go for
robotics and AI. First of all, it's a
really interesting field and secondly,
it has huge
potential. Rohan says the IIAF chief is
very angry with the with HAL. Is he
right? To a large extent he is right.
Hindustan Aeronautics Limited needs to
raise its standards. If the IIAF chief
is upset, if he's angry, look, you got
to take him seriously. The guy knows
what he's talking about. So yeah, to a
very large extent, I'm pretty sure that
he is quite
right. A Phoenix Music says, "Can you
give a brief on your physics research
topic? found out that your old research
base was just behind my hostel. Small
world. My old research base. Which one?
I've had multiple research bases. My
physics research topic was dark matter.
Um the role that primordial black holes
could potentially play as a dark matter
candidate. Not primordial black holes as
such but quantum me quantum mechanical
bound states of microscopic primordial
black holes that we call
holiums. And these could potentially be
stable. And if they did exist or they
did form in the very ancient in the very
early universe and and we there are
multiple scenarios that show that there
could have been an over production of of
microscopic primordial black holes in
the very early universe during the
pre-inflation phase as well as during
reheating recombination etc. So in such
scenarios there's a possibility that
primordial black holes could have formed
quantum mechanical bound states which
could be stable and in that case there
they could still exist today and they
could form a significant uh component of
the cold dark matter that we are hunting
for that. So that's that was my research
topic. Arian Thiagi says commerce
secretary Howard Howard Lui said that
India so that US did not like what India
did. uh not that India crossed the red
line. I misunderstood and asked. Okay.
I'm not sure what he didn't like. Once
again, I'm I haven't read that
particular piece of news. So, their
commerce secretary said that they did
not like what India did. What did we
do is the question. Did we negotiate too
hard? There's this negotiation that's
going on between India and the US about
the trade and tariff deal, right?
So did they not like the style of
negotiation? Did we not back down? Did
we not give into the maximalist demands?
What exactly is it that they did not
like? So uh I'm I'm not sure what it is.
If you know what is it it is that they
did not like then maybe I can throw more
light on it. Uh let me just because
since we're discussing maybe I'll do a
very quick Google search and see what it
is. Howard Lu3.
Howard
Lu3 India. What is it?
Howard Lutra.
Lutnik.
Lutnik. What is it?
Lutnik. US trade deal blah blah etc. Not
too distant future. India getting under
US skin by buying Russian arms. Oh, they
can take a hike if they have a problem.
Okay, maybe India is buying Russian
weapons. That's why they're not unhappy.
Well, they can take a hike. We are not a
US wasal. We're not a puppet. We are an
autonomous sovereign nation. If they
have a
problem, well, they can take the problem
and keep it where it belongs with them.
That's all I can
say. Kavia says uh was the Indian
judiciary and Indian constitution
designed to be against the interest of
bat and
Hindus? Well, I don't know about the
judiciary. So uh but the constitution is
entirely
unindian
unbarata. Look the
constitution ideally should be the soul
of a nation. Now for a nation like
bharat what is its soul? It is bharati.
that is the batya sanskriti the
civilization and culture of bhat which
means that India's constitution should
be founded should be grounded in Indian
culture Indian values Indian morality
and Indian ethics now if you examine the
Indian constitution it's entirely
western and abrahamic in
nature and it has it is said by
experts who find out it is said by
experts that there are certain sections
of the constitution
that are blatantly anti- anti-Indian
culture, anti-Indian civilization. So it
looks like the constitution for sure was
designed against the Indian interests of
bhat and
Hindus. Um and in case you all you all
are not aware the Indian constitution
was imposed undemocratically on India.
On the first page they write we the
people of India or something like that.
Right? My question is once the
constitution was drafted, why was it not
ratified by the people of India? Why
were the people of India not given the
chance to ratify
it? If it has not been ratified by the
people of India, it means it has been
imposed undemocratically. What does it
mean to be ratified? What does it mean?
It means that the people are given the
option to decide. Do you accept this
constitution or do you reject it? Which
means there has to be a referendum. Now
you will say according to the Indian
constitution there is no
referendum but before the constitution
was in was applied on India there was no
constitution. So there could have been a
referendum but there was no referendum.
See when the US constitution was written
it was put to a
vote. So who was able to vote? Wealthy
landowning white men were allowed to
vote which were the people that mattered
in the US in those days. So it was not
entirely democratic. It was highly
undemocratic but from their perspective
it was very democratic because there was
a vote. So the US constitution was
accepted by those who were allowed to
vote. In India there was no vote. So it
is an undemocratically imposed
constitution. Find me a single
constitutional expert who can disagree
with
me. He's manticor says is the next human
evolution going to evol involve genetic
engineering and the focus of AI
cybernetics. Is this a deviation from
centuries of natural evolution? Is it
okay? Well, it's definitely unnatural.
So, first of all, is the next human
evolution going to involve genetic
engineering and focus on AI and
cybernetics? I think
yes, genetic engineering is already kind
of happening. There is something called
crisper. That is kind of yesterday's
news. There's going to be more means of
of editing genes, of doing gene therapy
and so on so forth to improve uh your
genetic makeup. Such technologies are
already there. So there is that already.
AI, cybernetics, you have things like um
neural link chip implants. There are
chips that are implanted into your brain
tissue and that those can give you
enhanced cognitive capabilities,
enhanced perception and much more. So
they could turn you into a super human
being, super person, super superman,
superwoman. That's cybernetic technology
obviously. So excuse me. So all that is
already kind of uh on the on the table
right now. All those options are on the
table. Next 10 years there going to be
leaps and bounds that will be taken in
this direction. Is this this is a
deviation from centuries? Not centuries,
millions of years of natural evolution.
There is no evolution over 10 centuries,
20 centuries. Evolution is the effects
of evolution are only visible over time
spans of hundreds of thousand of
thousands of years at
minimum. So this is a deviation from
millions of years probably billions of
years of natural evolution. Is it okay?
Well, who decides it's okay or not? If
you can do it, you will do it.
So um there's no okay or not okay. It's
like geopolitics. There's no right or
wrong in geopolitics. Those who are
powerful will achieve their means their
their ends by whatever means they they
need to. Uh so yeah it's it's it's
there. Nanda Kizor says Cameroonians are
speaking Tamil Indian language in India.
Well I would congratulate our our great
friends in Cameroon that they are
learning an Indian language.
Outstanding. Uh, Sergeant Skylin says,
"Will Nvidia manufacturing come to
India?" Some of it may come to India,
but not the high-end chips. Absolutely
not. Why would they bring it to India?
Right. Grock says, "Will India make a
tactical hydrogen bomb like China?"
Look, what you call a hydrogen bomb is
better known as a thermonuclear bomb.
It's a two- stage or three-stage device.
There's an initial chemical explosion
essentially that triggers a primary fish
reaction and that fish reaction implodes
within to cause a secondary fusion
reaction that releases way more energy
than a fish reaction can. So the fish
reaction itself is a nuclear atomic
bomb. But then it gives rise to a fusion
reaction and that's the thermonuclear
part of it. So a thermonuclear bomb
which is colloially called a hydrogen
bomb is not a tactical weapon. It's a
weapon with a huge amount of energy that
is released. A tactical bomb is a small
scale nuclear weapon nuclear weapon
which is almost always a fish
device and its output is you know a
yield of in the kiloton range. So the
Hiroshima Nagasaki events those horrible
nuclear tests on human beings they had
an output of iron between 17 to 18 to 20
kilotons roughly in that range kilot of
TNT equivalent. Uh fusion bombs
thermonuclear fish and fusion bombs or
hydrogen bombs they typically have an
output that is multiples of that like 10
times that or something. So it probably
begins around 70 80 kilotons maybe 100
kilotons and it'll go into the megaton
range and the most powerful one was 50
megatons the tar bomba so will India
make it India already has thermonuclear
bomb capabilities
yeah
says Russia's economy is onetenth
China's yet it's the most powerful
second most powerful nation you said
it's largely due to its nukes what steps
could China take to close this power gap
with Russia and how long would it take?
See, a hard power score has multiple
components and if you assign a certain
amount of weight to nuclear weapons,
then nuclear weapons will tip the
balance in a certain direction. So the
way I have calculated it, Russia's
enormous nuclear arsenal gives it the
second rank. Now, if you choose to
calculate it differently, it could make
China number two. It's entirely up to
you. From my perspective, nuclear
weapons are a significant uh factor in
hard power. So based on the way I have
chosen to
um to create the formula, the equation
not the equation, the formula for hard
power. It's an equation. So based on
that, Russia is number two largely due
to its enormous nuclear arsenal. What
steps should China take to close this
power gap?
increase the size of your nuclear
arsenal. There's nothing else. That's
it. How long would it take? It could
take them maybe 10 years. Depending on
how much file material they have access
to, uh I'm sure they have access to
uranium. I think one of the reasons why
they why they why they hold on to axin
is because there is uranium there. So if
they have access to sufficient uranium
they could close the gap in maybe 10
years 20 years depends right. So there
you have it. SK 100 sorry says do you
believe in a tripolar world China and
Russia would not let a third power rise.
Uh China and the US would not let a
third power rise which will cause
instability in the world. I read
tripolar instability from Robert S.
Slutwak. Okay. Uh, love from SE. Uh, you
mean South Korea? I suppose. Okay.
Singapore. Not
sure. Uh, so do I believe in a tripod
world? I believe in a multiple world. I
believe in any kind of world that's
possible. Um, it's obviously true that
the Chinese and the US will see eye to
eye on one thing and one thing only that
no third power should rise to a level
that's comparable to the two of them.
Right? they will agree on that and
that's why they both agree that Pakistan
needs to continue to exist and they both
are okay with and they both want India
to not destroy Pakistan.
So uh they both would very much not want
India to rise beyond certain limits
right and from their perspective it will
cause instability or maybe it will cause
stability it'll make the world more
stable if there are three powers uh you
know the most stable world is a monopol
uniolar world but it's a horrible world
the world is beautiful when you have so
much so much diversity in nations and
the different kinds of power that you
have
Um but uh from from the largest powers
perspective, more powers rising means
more
instability. Um so that's how it is. Do
I believe in it? Look, it's possible
that it exists that it can exist and it
would be good actually for India to
rise. It would be good for the world. So
maybe a tripolar world will be better
for the world actually if if three if
there are three great powers instead of
just two. And you may have a fourpolar
world actually tripolar quadripolar
world if Russia also becomes
um you know an economic power in
addition to being a military and nuclear
uh
power. Wamshi says will the US allow us
to become a monarchy now? Is it too
risky? The US doesn't want anything to
change in India. And if there's a chance
of India becoming a monarchy, it's a
very very very unlikely far-off
scenario. But if there's a if if there's
a chance that happens, then maybe the
Americans will try to play some regime
change kind of operation. Maybe try and
interfere within India. And they have
lots of assets within India. I assure
you of that. So they will not allow they
would ideally not want to allow anything
within India to change. They want India
to be in a steady state system.
They don't want an expanding India. They
don't want they want a steadystate
India. They want a gnarly ho situation
for
India. Uh not the other situation
expanding
India. Nandanda Kisar says, "How did the
US get rich in the 19th century? Was it
due to Indian wealth funnels through the
British Empire? Did the US fund both
sides in World War II?" Look, the US got
wealthy for multiple reasons.
Some of the British folks who plundered
wealth from India, some of them may have
ended up in the
US. But you can't attribute America's
success to to Indian wealth stolen from
India. No, the US, you know what is the
true wealth of the US, the land. They
have a continent-sized nation that was
stolen from its original inhabitants who
were genocided out of existence and
those who remained were put in
concentration camps where they still
remain which are called reservations and
they are secondass citizens more or less
even today unless they have become white
and they've become racially diluted. So
they became rich because of the enormous
land they have which is full of all
kinds of
resources. Right? That's number one. And
number two, in the second world war,
first world war, second world war, they
were insulated from all the problems
because of two enormous oceans that
flanked them on two
sides. And they were able to, you could
say, fund both sides to a large extent,
you know. Yeah. And the second world
war, that is the event that completely
transformed the US economy. The military
industrial complex was born in that
time. So that's that's kind of the long
and the short of it. A TLDDR version of
what
happened. Robert Cool. Thank you very
much. First of all, let me try and read
this. I'm very slow at Hindi.
Namaste.
Historically, Hungary, Czechoslovakia,
Manuria,
Georgia. Okay. R Hungary is Hungary part
of the
West. Nobody will call Hungary a western
nation. It's an Eastern European nation.
Czechoslovakia again Eastern European.
Manuria, it's currently part of China.
China's far east, north of North Korea.
Georgia, it's not the West. It's it's
the Caucasus region. Historically, it's
kind of
Asia, right? What is the West? The West
is Germany, France, Italy, the UK, the
Netherlands, and so on. Has Russia ever
attacked those nations? Of course,
Russia was an
empire and it's okay for a nation to be
an empire. The Mongols were an empire.
We used to be an empire. As an empire,
you do certain things. Russia has
expanded eastwards. It had expanded all
the way to Alaska before the Americans
before the British even reached that
place.
Um so yeah, they they brought Hungary
into their uh into their sphere of
influence. Hungary was a satellite
state, a vasal state of Russia. So was
Czechoslovakia. So was Poland. So were
uh so was Hungary and so were many other
nations. And they did regime change
operations. They did sometimes invade
some of them and so on. You do these
things as an as an empire, as a
superpower. When the US does it, nobody
raises raises an eye eyelid eyebrow. But
when Russia does something big deal. Has
Russia ever invaded Germany? Has Russia
ever invaded Italy? Has Russia ever
invaded
U France? Has Russia ever? So the
Western European nations never been
invaded by Russia. Manuria is not the
west, right? Manuria is not the west.
And so what happened in Manuria, the
Russian expansion in the region that
that happened over the over last I don't
know three centuries or so. Old history.
If you bring out old history, all kinds
of things come out of that, right? So,
so
okay. Okay. Anka says Mr. Trump's tariff
war beneficial or harmful for the US
economy in the long run. I think it
could end up being harmful trade and
tariff war. I mean he it's I can
understand him trying to impose tariffs
on China. Makes sense from his
perspective from the US perspective. I
can understand him trying to bully India
on tariffs. We are not an ally or a
vasal of the US. So it's okay for them
to bully bully us. He is bullying the EU
nations who are his
vasals. Why would you do that? You have
a good existing relationship and you own
the US dollar. So it doesn't matter what
the European nations do. They're anyway
trading in the US dollar
mostly. They have the euro which is
again a vasal of the dollar. So I'm not
sure what's the objective of bullying
the EU nations or the NATO
nations. It's going to create disscent.
It's going to create this desire to
break free of the US which will not work
of course but it will cause frictions
and all kinds of unnecessary troubles. I
think overall in the long run it's
harmful for the US economy unless he
believes that you know there's long no
long-term future for Europe which the
Americans seem to be kind of
engineering. Um so it's fine to
disengage from China from Russia and so
on. And this disengagement is is
happening as we speak and it's a US
engineered disengagement this this you
know this bipolarization of the world
that we are seeing right now but why do
it to to your allies in Europe and so
on. I think it could be harmful to the
US economy in the long run unless they
believe that you know at the end of the
day in a few years all nations are going
to be isolated and insulated from each
other and uh that's kind of a siege
mentality kind of approach. I think in
the long run if this persists it's going
to be harmful to the US economy in the
long
run. He's manticor says is the US trying
to delay FE 404 engines footages?
They're not trying to delay it. They are
delaying it. It's not a try. It's it's
happening. It's it's already delayed.
Significantly delayed. We have paid for
it. We have paid good good money for it
and they are dragging their feet over
it. So they are already doing it.
They're not trying it. They are actively
delaying the
engines. Bavik Vada says, "Uh, what do
you think Alberta's future will be if it
separates from Canada? I see this
sentiment of separation all around me
now. Will the US step in to annex
Alberta? If that happens, I can
understand Quebec wanting to separate
from Canada because they are culturally,
linguistically separate. Ethnically,
also, historically, they are French. The
rest of Canada is of mainly British
origin mainly, I'm saying.
Um and and Quebec has come close to to
you know seceding from Canada at least a
couple of times. But Alberta when why
would Alberta want to secede from
Canada but you are there apparently on
the ground and you see the sentiment all
around you. It what it indicates is that
you know
Canada the truth is Canada is an
artificial nation. It's a
nation
that's that has been created out of
stolen land, out of the genocide of the
natives and whoever survived has been
relegated to secondass citizen
status. And what is it that binds a
nation together? What when it comes to
India, it's our culture and civilization
that binds us together. No matter what
language we speak, no matter what part
of India we live in, we still have this
common civilizational thread and we
understand each other and we are part of
when we all have the same ancestry going
back tens of thousands of
years. So that binds us together. When
it comes to Canada, what binds the
people of Canada together? Is there some
kind of shared culture or something?
There's nothing of the sort. So it makes
sense for this this sentiment to be
there. It means that there is no
long-term future for this artificial
nation. In a 100 years, you may not have
any Canada anymore. Maybe in 10 years,
you may not have it. If Trump decides to
make a move on Canada, your hypothetical
question is that if
Alberta separates, secedes from Canada,
what will happen? Will the US step in to
annex
Alberta? I see no reason why they would
not. I mean, the US could step in and
annex annex the whole of Canada
tomorrow, and there's nothing Canada can
do about it.
Uh so yeah it's possible if Alberta
secedes from Canada the the Americans
will step in and annex Alberta and maybe
the Albertans will actually be happy for
a change about that if it happens.
Yeah. Rahul Lakman says can you explain
Wolf Wolf Rams
hyperraphs could it potentially be a
theory for everything? I have never
studied that stuff. I don't know what it
is. Yeah he Mr. Mr. Wrang he's a super
intelligent guy and he has created one
of the best uh scientific softwares of
all time Mathematica super powerful
software and it takes a lot of time to
learn it learn how to use it super
powerful software brilliant guy no
question about it and I have not delved
into what these hyperraphs are and
apparently it looks like he he claims
that it is a theory of everything which
explains everything but I haven't really
looked into it thus far So can't say
anything beyond
that. Raj Kanakatu says why not explore
Sanskrit for secure defense
coding. Well look Sanskrit is not a
programming language. You know it's it's
way too complex for that.
Um doesn't make sense. Secure defense
coding. You know security in defense
comes not from the language that you use
for coding. Security comes from the
measures you take to prevent others from
breaking into your
systems. Okay. So it's it's it's your
security measures to insulate your
sensitive and critical systems from
outside threats that matter which could
involve air gapping which could involve
all kinds of other other measures. It
has absolutely nothing to do with the
programming language. Of course, you
need to
have you need to have all the best
practices that you know that are adopted
in coding. As long as you do it, it's
fine. Whether you call in Python or oh
or C or C or whatever you
want. Grock says China made non-nuclear
hydrogen bomb made of
magnesium. A non- nuclear hydrogen bomb
made of magnesium. If it is made of
magnesium, then how is it a hydrogen
bomb? Because magnesium is a metallic
element and hydrogen is the lightest
element. These are totally different
elements here. Uh maybe there's some
magnesium component to it. Um I'm not
aware of it. Okay. Non- nuclear hydrogen
bomb, which means it's a bomb that has
hydrogen as one of the components, which
is possibly the explosive component. I'm
not
sure. Vijay Jooshi says, "What's the
controversy of 905 of Quran?" I have
never read the Quran. I am not familiar
with it at all. So I am not the right
person to ask this question. Sorry. I
have absolutely no idea about it. Jurgen
says after India deep penetration
strikes against inside Pakistan why the
US suddenly turned against India. Today
also Trump's adviser is openly
threatening to cut off ties with Russia
breaks detoization
etc. Look Pakistan is very important for
the US. They don't want India to rise
which means they need a nation like
Pakistan, East Pakistan, West Pakistan
to keep India unstable to keep India off
balance. If Pakistan is destroyed, then
that enormous leverage they've
cultivated over decades is is gone. It
it
evaporates. So the Americans never
expected that India will strike so hard
against Pakistan and hit 11 air bases in
20 minutes and strike hundreds of strike
hundreds of kilometers deep within
Pakistan. hit Pakistan's secure hardened
uh uh nuclear warhead storage sites and
so on. It was I think the Americans when
they realized what India was doing they
probably had a panic attack that we're
going to lose our asset Pakistan. It
looked like we could be in PK in 24 to
48 hours. Right? It looked like that
because Pakistan was vulnerable. It was
rendered helpless and defenseless by the
strikes. We wiped out the many of the
radar systems. We wiped out their air
defense systems. We destroyed their
their their many of their military
installations, their air bases. We
created the runways which means their
their fighter planes could not take off.
They were sitting
ducks. They had been rendered helpless
by India. That's why Americans
panicked otherwise they would have lost
their valuable strategic asset. That's
why they did this. Right now, Trump's
adviser is threatening to cut off ties
with Russia. Breaks. Okay, they they
issue threats all the time. They are the
most powerful nation in the world. They
can issue threats and they can actually
you know implement the threats if they
want. So you have to take them
seriously. Suy Singh, thank you very
much. Thank you. Saita says we should
club important services like ISRO
DIS and give facilities high packages
etc. Do you think such salary in
government cause brain drain corruption?
You know one of the best ways
um to reverse the brain drain to address
the issue of the brain drain is to give
high salaries to
people. What's a salary? It's the value
you ascribe to a person. If you pay a
person more it means you value the value
the person
more than any honors, more than any kind
words. The a person values the salary
they're given. Right? So if you can give
salaries comparable to what you would
get in NASA or or in SpaceX or in the US
government then who will go? Nobody will
go if you treat people like with the
value that they deserve. So I think yeah
it makes sense but then the question is
can India afford to give such high
salaries to so many people and so
on. So yeah it makes sense to do that
actually. Pranav thank you very much sir
I really appreciate your kind words and
your contribution thank you so much
sir power says if buying F-35 gives
access to Americans isn't if already
doing so with Chinuk apache MQ9 etc all
under the same IAF umbrella giving
access
yeah it does it does mean that and we
should ensure it doesn't go further than
this so we have the Apache but we
already we also have the the the LCH
helicopter which is superior to the to
the Apache in our conditions. The Apache
can't take off from Lei. It can't fight
a battle you know it cannot operate at
the altitudes that we have in the Lelay
region in the in the the the Indo Indo
Tibet undemarced border
region. So we have a superior
helicopter. So whatever Apaches we have
bought it's enough. We can use them
against Pakistan potentially if the
Americans don't use the kill switch. The
MQ9's again we have to develop our
indigenous systems. We cannot keep on
buying foreign
equipment that too from a nation that
has a proven track record of of uh you
know of playing these games of using
kill switches and and denying full use
of of military equipment to their
allies. So we cannot afford to buy the
F-35. It'll be a disaster. Adita sir,
thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Airpantore says China doesn't want its
single men to marry foreign brides,
especially from Bangladesh and Pakistan.
Apparently, there's an agency in both
countries that market the Chinese men as
pure Muslims.
WTF?
Okay. I'm not aware of these things.
China Pakistan and
Bangladesh, foreign brides. Um so China
has this issue right? Uh they have this
declining population but I don't think
any number of foreign brides will solve
that problem and if you bring in foreign
brides from these countries these
radicalized countries it will be a
bigger problem for China. So it makes
sense that China doesn't want its men to
single men to marry these foreign brides
brides and there's an agency in Pakistan
and in Bangladesh that markets Chinese
men as pure Muslims. What on earth?
Yeah. A very very interesting piece of
news here. Time boxing says Suesh Singh
versus time blocking. More efficient
method. Time blocking. Time
boxing. I am aware of time blocking. I
think it's a pretty good method. Not
sure about time boxing. So I would my
vote will go for time blocking.
Spartan Bhagwa says, "Is it is it okay
for men to do a basic skincare routine,
style their hair while being physically
strong and capable?" I feel Indian guys
have a lot of potential. I think it is
perfectly okay for you to be concerned
about your appearance and to and to want
to have a better appearance. Yes, you
should have a skincare routine. Not
waste your entire day looking after your
skin and all, but but do take care of
your skin. basic skincare routine.
Absolutely. Once a day, twice a day. If
you what's wrong with styling your hair,
absolutely style your hair and be
physically strong, capable, all of that.
Absolutely. I completely agree with you.
It is perfectly 100% okay. Not just
okay, it is recommended that men should
do
this. Warriors, does the world think
India won? Who is being being
manipulated
more my by by my my government India or
Pakistan? Why do Pakistanis say the one?
Why so much sudden hate against India?
The more India rises, the more India
will get hate. We aren't we are the
world's most ancient civilization. We
are the only remaining polytheistic
civilization. The whole world is
essentially Abrahamic and monotheistic.
The whole world is ruled by them and
they are deeply unhappy that we are
still we still exist. when everything
else has fallen. The western
monotheists, they had polytheistic
cultures. Their culture was an offshoot
of ours and it's been smashed out of
existence. But we are still standing.
How dare we still stand? That's why
there is hate against India. And they
occupied us for 250 years, the British,
and they drained everything of value out
of India. And yet here we still are.
We're again on our feet. We we're again
rising. How dare
we rise? How dare we? And they are
actually afraid because they know what
we're capable of. For the majority of
history, we were the largest economy. So
that's why there is this outpouring of
hatred against us on social media and so
on. Who does the think this is a world
thing India? I don't care what the world
thinks. But of course, we should uh we
should put forth our our truth to the
world that we did one. We did win. We
did hammer Pakistan. We rendered them
completely defenseless and
helpless. Who is being manipulated more
by government? India or Pakistan? Why do
Pakistanis think say they won? Because
Pakistanis love to lie. That's why.
Suchin says
um admir thank you very much. My
brutally honest opinion of did Modi
chicken out from finishing of Pakistan
under US China pressure. It's not called
chickening out. When the world's most
powerful nation decides, it tells you
that we will destroy you unless you back
off. You have to back off. It's not
called chickening
out. If if Mr. Modi had not backed off,
then the Americans would have destroyed
India's economy through a variety of
means. They are perfectly capable of
turning India into Venezuela or Iran or
North Korea in a matter of days or weeks
through simply through purely economic
means.
Mr. Modi did the right thing. When the
Americans issue a threat, you have to
take it seriously. You back up. You back
down. So, I don't think Mr. Modi is
chickened out. He has done the right
thing for the country. It's very
disappointing. Very disappointing that
we had to stop the war at the 3-day
stage. Very disappointing. It is not Mr.
Modi's
fault. It is Trump's
fault. And if this was not done, they
would have destroyed us. Please
understand how powerful the US is.
Sitting here we don't realize how
powerful the US is because the US
hides its means. They are tremendously
powerful
nation. Ryik says does India have the
infrastructure to absorb Russian SU57
technology and massproduce it? I have
watched a IM said that we probably do or
don't. I don't know what anybody has
said. We have absorbed the Russian Sukoy
30 technology.
So why can't we do the same thing with
the SOA 57 especially when there there
is significant overlap and interoperable
operability? I think India will be able
to take the S57 technology the transfer
of technology and mass produce the
aircraft. I am very confident we'll be
able to do
it. So yeah that's my that's my answer.
Um what are the challenges? You know
some of the things may have changed. We
know how to handle the Sukoy 30. Now
this this new aircraft is different.
It's a Suko aircraft. So there'll be
lots of similarities in certain basic
things but many of the weapon systems
will be different and we'll have to
integrate our weapon systems, our
radars, our missiles, etc. with the Suko
57. Uh which may be a challenge. You
know we have very dangerous air-to-air
missiles like the Astra beyond visual
range air-to-air missile and and various
other harm missiles, anti-radiation
missiles and so on so forth. how to
integrate all missiles with this system
is going to be obviously it's going to
uh need some
work but I think we will be very much
able to handle this ma this matter and
mass produce this
aircraft. Uh Dr. Rituknak says why do a
certain community in Bollywood support
Palestine whether whereas we have
nothing to gain from them. Is it to
disturb this Israelind India
relationship? Look I don't know I don't
get into religious issues. Okay. I don't
talk about internal political and
religious matters of
India. Uh I agree that we have nothing
to gain from Palestine from supporting
Palestine and so on. So yeah, what
whatever it is, look, Bollywood, we have
to stop idolizing Bollywood. That's what
I would say. You cannot waste your time
idolizing entertainers. They're the last
people you should
idolize. Suchin says throughout
operation sindor we have we were trying
to claim the high moral ground in and in
process lost precious jets in the
opening salvo by not neutralizing
radars. Please understand during a mo
during a military operation you're not
trying to claim high borrowed
ground. Okay. You have some assumptions.
You have some intelligence. You have
some data. Based on that you do certain
things. Some things work. Some things
don't work. Then you adapt your tactics.
And then you either succeed or
fail. I don't know how many jets we
lost. Whether it's five, whether it's
50, whether it's zero. I don't know what
what the the chief of defense staff or
whatever
he you know whatever was said. I'm not
sure what was said. I don't understand
what was being
said. So I'm not even sure even today if
we have actually lost jets. But let's
say we lost two jets hypothetically. So
what? It's a godamned war. You're going
to lose stuff in war. Every day on the
border, there's firing from Pakistan,
firing from India. We lose soldiers from
routine basis. Every every every few
days there's a casualty or two. Do we
cry about that? This is warfare. This is
a serious matter matter. You're going to
lose equipment. Why are Indians
constantly crying about
this? Only if nobody dies. Only if not a
single piece of equipment is damaged.
Then only we have won.
That's not how it works. And how do you
know that we have not utiliz we did not
start neutralizing radars on day one?
How do you know that? So let's not make
assumptions and let's not be such
defeist people. I am okay with losing
fighter
jets. The Americans fighting the Houthis
lost two F18 fighter planes. fighting
the
Houthies, a rebel
force. Okay. Mlevin says, "Why does
India lack aesthetics?" Because India is
poor. Poverty is
unesthetic. You understand? What needs
to happen is India needs to become a
higher GDP per capita nation. Then we
will be able to spend time on
beautifying ourselves and spend money on
beautifying ourselves. Right now
aesthetics are a luxury most Indians
can't afford and the government is not
interested
in. The government is in the bureaucrats
who are in charge of everything. So even
today if you go to these old to the
cities that were colonized by the
British even today you will find that
the colonial architecture is
aesthetically superior to anything we
built after 1947 because the people in
charge of running the country and making
decisions had no sense of
aesthetics. So two problems one is
poverty and secondly the people who are
in charge of running the country have no
sense of aesthetics because we are
promoting the wrong
people. Suchin says, "So if Pakistan is
enjoying um US China patronage and we
cannot anger the joint duo, then are you
predicting that we will be forced to
restart water supply via industry?" I am
not predicting that.
Nope.
Look, they will be like you say angry
anger only if we we we try to destroy
Pakistan. But squeezing Pakistan and
applying pressure on Pakistan they will
try and come in the way but they will
not be able to stop us from um
suspending continuing the suspension of
the industry. I have already said today
in the previous live stream that there
is a 70% probability that this
continues that the Indust treaty
suspension stays and there's about a 20%
or whatever it was probability that we
may conditionally temporarily lift lift
the suspension only if Pakistan
demonstrates with proof that they are
taking action in dismantling terrorist
infrastructure and eliminating terrorist
assets which is not going to happen. So
India is not going to restart water
supply. No matter what the Americans say
or China China
says please understand
nuances. Please understand
nuances. We came close to destroying
Pakistan. That's why the Americans
stepped in and issued some kind of very
dire threat. And that's why Mr. Modi had
to pause the
war. The Indust treaty was not part of
the issue. That suspension happened
before. So it's a different topic
here. Arismantic horses Trump Pakistan
crypto deal like Biden Ukraine bribes.
Kind of like that. Kind
of. Uh Aerosmantic says let's set our
standards higher. No more chelga BS. I
completely agree with you sir.
Completely agree. Thank you for saying
that and please put that in action.
Ritwick says, "Are we getting more
episodes with Ram Diwi?" He had two
shots explaining uh how western media
tried to shape the narrative against
Obindur. Uh we will see about that.
We'll see. I am perfectly happy to do
episodes
with
all good analysts and interesting
people. We'll see about
that. Warrior says, "Why do people blame
Jews for world control 911, etc.
Um not sure why they do. You know, one
of the reasons could possibly be because
Israel is America's number one ally.
America offers unconditional support to
Israel. And maybe that's why people make
such such claims. I'm not sure why they
do that. Uh I am not sure if there is
any evidence whatsoever that links the
Jewish people to the 911 thing. But I
don't know. People make all kinds of
claims. What can I do about it?
Sparta Spartan Bhagwa says, "Should we
become an organized religion just to
survive the monotheistic onslaught? Why
Indians are suffering from clueless
pagan syndrome even after 10,000
years?" You know, when you come under
attack, under assault, you change and
our culture has already changed a lot in
the past 10,000 years. I mean, look at
the the kind of dress we wear today.
Look at the kind of dress ladies wear in
India today. and look at how how our
ancestors were dressed 10,000 years ago.
That's just just one example of change.
Look at the kind of linguistic influence
we've had and so on so forth, you know.
Um so maybe maybe to survive the
monotheistic on we may perhaps have to
evolve in certain ways. Maybe you only
can fight fire with fire. So maybe maybe
we should become more organized. I would
not say we should become a completely
you know pyramidal structure a top- down
military mil military organization
structure the the way the Abrahamic
religions are but there should be more
organization more cohesion more unity
which can only come with the proper
leadership so at least some of that is
needed and with this will be the last
question for today suchin says the
reason why we are so worried about
precious jets is because we have so few
if China has learned our weakness it
will try take the rest out in the next
round. There's always
threats. We live in a an environment
with significant threats. There are
multiple threat scenarios. Our jets are
precious. You're right. We have very
few. But when you decide to go to war,
you're going to have some loss of
equipment. It's it's part of the deal.
It's part of war. I mean, in 1971, how
many aircraft did we lose? More than 40.
We lost more than 40 fighter aircraft in
1971. But who won the war? We did. In
the Cargill war, we lost at least two
fighter aircraft if I am not mistaken.
The Cargill war. But we won the war. So
look, yeah, it's true. We have not
sufficient numbers of fighter aircraft.
We should have more. So we need to work
on that. But it doesn't mean we don't go
to war and we don't use the aircraft in
war. When you are in a war situation,
you use everything at at your disposal.
And sometimes will some things will
obviously not go entirely your way. That
is part of the game. So once you are in
a war situation, you forget about the
precious numbers and all. You just use
whatever you have at your disposal.
Later you deal with whatever happened in
the war. So now we need more fighter
planes. I say buy the Suka 57. Negotiate
with with the Russians. See their offer.
Analyze the offer. Scrutinize it in
great detail. Amend the off. Ask them to
amend the offer if required and find a
solution or find a way forward that is
acceptable to both nations. Acquire the
technology have the entire airropot
manufactured in India. Manufactured 100
200 whatever number makes sense and
that's the way to go forward also at the
same time develop the AMCA develop the
M2 develop develop whatever air is
required. That's the way forward. That's
how to go. And there's one more super
chat. I'll take this one. Jagan says,
"Why is our government not exploring
critical minerals inside India? We are a
big country and why are we lacking to
lacking to crack crystal braid
technology for fighter jets? What about
our metal energy engineering? We have
very
poor engineering departments in much of
the country. Um, not up to world
standards. Okay, that's the truth. Metal
energy, I mean we have good basic metal
energy, but we're talking about cutting
edge bleeding edge metal metal energy
over here. Uh so that's why we are
behind in the
crystal single crystal blade fighter you
know jet turbine blade technology. It
takes time to develop that. Even the
developed nations took decades to
develop
that. Why is the government not
exploring critical minerals inside
India? We are a huge country. We should
I think there needs to be more
exploration more more prospecting. I
think if we look properly we will find
lots of oil and gas too and we may end
up becoming a net exporter of energy if
we just look carefully. We are a
gigantic country. Our onshore offshore
resources of oil and gas other things
will be tremendous. I think we have not
done any anything thus far to do proper
prospecting. So I agree with you. We
need to do that. All right friends, I am
at the end of
today's episode. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate all your questions. I
really appreciate your participation and
I will see you in tomorrow's live
stream. So until then, take care, keep
asking the questions and keep learning
and keep raising your standards. Good
day, good night wherever you are. I'll
see you very soon. Thank you. Bye-bye.